Young Master
公子
Taozi Chen Xing
桃子 陈醒
It’s been a hard journey
一路辛苦了
How is your father's health?
父帅身体如何
Report back to the young master
回禀公子
Lord Shang was originally suffering from wind-cold disorder.
主上原是风寒失调
When attacking Hanzhou
攻打涵州的时候
Opened old wounds again
又震裂了旧伤
so
所以
Recuperated for a while
调养了一段时日
But it's no big deal now
不过现下已无大碍
Don't worry, sir.
公子不用担心
My lord, I miss you and the captain very much.
主上十分挂念您和校尉
speak
言道
The young master has old wounds on his body
公子身上有旧伤
There is no one around the captain to take care of him
校尉身边又乏人照应
So I sent Chen Xing and me immediately
所以立时遣我和陈醒
Return to the army
返回军前
The captain is missing
校尉失踪了
What
什么
But fortunately
不过万幸的是
You are back safely now
你如今平安回来
I'm afraid this world
恐怕这天下
Only you have a way
只有你有法子
Can find her
能找到她了
Don't worry, sir.
公子不用担心
Only the captain
只要校尉
Still using that powder
仍旧用那种药粉
I will definitely find her
我就一定能找到她
explain
说
You two are sneaky
你们俩鬼鬼祟祟的
What are you doing here on our mountain?
来俺们山上干吗
Big brother
大哥
I see these two people
我看这俩人
Wearing leather boots
穿的都是皮靴
They must be two fat sheep
定是两只肥羊
This girl disguised as a man
这个女扮男装的女娘
good looking
长得好看
Big brother
大哥
You don’t have Mrs. Yazhai yet
你还没有压寨夫人
It's better to marry and be a wife
不如 娶了当夫人
Married as a wife
对 娶了当夫人
Married to be a lady
娶了 当夫人
exchange money
换钱
married
娶了
Shut up
闭嘴
who is the boss
谁是老大
Big brother
大哥
you
你
tell me honestly
老实告诉我
who are you
你是什么人
Let me tell you the truth
实话告诉你吧
actually i am
其实我是
The concubine of the emperor's grandson Li Ni
皇孙李嶷的爱妾
My husband-in-law is not only the grandson of the emperor
我的夫婿不仅是皇孙
Still famous
还是赫赫有名的
Counterinsurgency Marshal
平叛元帅
young
年纪轻轻
Then he led the various prefectures in the west of Zhenxi
便领镇西诸府
Command an army of 100,000
统大军十万
This is one hundred thousand
这 十万啊
real or fake
真的假的
My husband at this moment
我的夫婿此刻
Inside Wangzhou City
正在望州城里面
As long as you let me go
只要你们把我放了
I will definitely give you a lot of money
必定奉上钱财万贯
Nonsense
胡 胡说八道
you
你
you say
你说
Who is she?
她到底是什么人
she is
她是
The concubine of the emperor's grandson Li Ni
皇孙李嶷的爱妾
Then I will naturally be her guardian
那我自然是她的护卫
I'm on the order of the emperor's grandson
我奉皇孙之命
Protect her to Wangzhou
护她去望州
This emperor’s family
这皇帝老儿一家
Weren't they all killed?
不都给杀光了吗
you are here
你们在这儿
Open your mouth and talk nonsense
张嘴胡说八道
What are you talking about, the grandson of the emperor?
说什么皇孙
Do you think we are easy to deceive?
以为俺们是好骗的吗
that is
就是
Lie to us, lie to us
对 骗我们 骗俺们
Want to lie to us
想骗我们
Big brother
大哥
This girl kept saying
这女娘口口声声说
Her husband-in-law is Marshal of Zhenxi
她夫婿是镇西元帅
Our second brother Zhao
我们赵二哥
Wasn't he once in the Zhenxi Army?
不是曾经在镇西军中吗
Not as good as
不如
Let's invite Brother Zhao out
我们把赵二哥请出来
Distinguish between true and false
辨辨真假
Go and invite the second brother to come
去请二哥来
Where did this little thief come from?
是哪里来的小贼
Dare to pretend to be a member of our Zhenxi Army?
敢冒充我镇西军中人
Second brother
二哥
Second brother, this
二哥 这
Jushichiro
十七郎
It's really you, brother
真的是你啊 兄弟
Untie it quickly
快 快解开
Untie it quickly, quickly
快快快 快解开
untie untie
解开 解开
He turned out to be Li Ni, the seventeenth grandson of the emperor
他竟然是皇孙十七郎李嶷
Are you okay? I'll do it.
你行不行 不行我来
Slow down, slow down, slow down
慢点 慢点 慢点
Tie this woman up tight
把 把这女的绑紧 绑紧
Hurry up, tie it up tighter
快快快 绑紧点啊
Tighter, tighter
紧点 紧点
Don't let her run too hard
别让她跑了 使劲
This is my town's Western Army
这是我镇西军
A member of the scout team back then
当年一个斥候小队的
brother
兄弟
Let’s go deep into Moxi together
我们一起深入漠西
To spy on the military situation of the Tattoo Army
去刺探黥军的军情
Twelve people in total
一共十二个人
Before touching the king's tent
摸到王帐之前
last alive
最后活着的
Just me and him
只有我跟他
I lost an arm
我丢了一条胳膊
It's Shishiro
是十七郎
Carry me across the entire desert
背着我穿过整个大漠
Back to camp
回到营中
Second brother, this second brother
二哥 这 二哥
He is my savior
他是我的救命恩人
benefactor
恩人
benefactor benefactor benefactor
恩人 恩人 恩人
Come
来
All brothers
都是兄弟
Don't say such nonsense
不要说这见外的话
brother
兄弟
Come, come, come
来来来
Go ahead
干 干
dry dry dry
干干干
happy
痛快
Jushichiro
十七郎
You used to always brag to me
之前你总是跟我吹牛
He said your father is a landlord in Jiangbei
说你爹是江北的地主
The family has sixteen acres of fertile land
家里足足有十六亩良田
And four top-quality oxen
还有四头上等的黄牛
He said his father was a landlord in Jiangbei
他说他爹是江北的地主
Do you really believe it?
你们还真信
Of course I don’t believe it
当然不信
If he is the son of a landlord
他要是地主家的儿子
I am the emperor and his second uncle
我就是皇帝他二大爷
Second uncle
二大爷
You are really senior
你辈分还真高
You girl
你这个女娘
Don't be chirpy
不要叽叽歪歪
Talk again
再说话
I'll shut your mouth
俺就把你嘴堵上
brother
兄弟
What else did you say
你还说过什么
You said you won't be a soldier when you wait
你说等你不当兵了
I have to go home and be a farm servant.
就要回家做田舍翁
Collect rent from people every day
天天跟人收租子
did not expect
没想到
We can still meet here
咱们还能在这儿见面
Jushichiro
十七郎
I, Huang Youyi
俺黄有义
The most respected in my life
生平最敬重
A kindhearted hero
有情有义的英雄
I heard what my second brother said today
今日听了二弟一番话
I just realized you were guarding the border
才知道你是守边关
The Zhenxi Army that fought against the Tattoo Army
打黥军的镇西军
Saved my second brother’s life again
又救过我二弟的性命
It makes us want to join the Zhenxi Army even more
更让我们想投奔镇西军
today
今日
I can't wait
是我等不对
here
在这儿
Make amends first
先行赔罪
Get up quickly
快起来
Let the brothers also get up
让弟兄们也起来
Get up, everyone
都起来吧
this time
这次
It's a misunderstanding
是个误会
I'd like to toast all brothers
我敬各位兄弟一杯
Come
来
Dry
干
general
将军
This is the Cui family army
这是那崔家军
He Xiaowei's horse
何校尉的马
Since the horse is here
马既然在此
People must not have run far yet
人必然还没跑远
This mountain is densely forested
这山林密集
Our army spent another tiring night
我军又劳顿一夜
I'm afraid it will be difficult to catch up
恐怕难以追上
general
将军
why us
为何我们
Not directly retaking Wangzhou City
不直接夺回望州城
The army in Zhenxi is strong and strong
镇西军兵强马壮
Cui Jiajun is watching with eager eyes
崔家军虎视眈眈
The enemy is strong and we are weak, so we cannot attack forcefully.
敌强我弱 不可硬攻
The only way is to capture General Pei first.
只有先拿住小裴将军
He Xiaowei
和何校尉
These two important people
这两个要紧的人物
Only then can we exchange for the city.
才能去换回城池
At this time we are exhausted
此时我们人困马乏
The camp was burned down again
大营又被火烧了
He also hurt many brothers
还伤了不少兄弟
Keep it like this
照这样下去
Those two important people didn't catch up
那两个紧要人物没追上
Everyone
大伙
But I'm trapped in this mountain
却被困倒在这山里了
nearby
这附近
Is there any place
有没有什么地方
You can rest
可以歇脚
This Mingdai Mountain area
这明岱山一带
There is a group of bandits
有一伙山匪
Self-built cottage
自建山寨
Be the king of the mountain
占山为王
I don’t usually disturb people.
平时倒不扰民
so
所以
Our Wangzhou garrison
我们望州守军
That's why we didn't wipe them out.
也就没剿灭他们
Send an order
传令
Capture the mountain stronghold first
先攻下山寨
Our army camp was burned
我军大营被烧
There's no place to stay anymore
已经没了落脚的地方
Recuperate first, occupy the mountain and become king
先休养生息 占山为王
Waiting for Governor Sun
等待孙大都督的
Reinforcements are coming
援军前来
yes
是
Jushichiro
十七郎
where did you come from this time
这次 你是从哪儿来
Where are you going?
打算去哪儿呢
Brother Zhao
赵二哥
Seventeen Lang this time
十七郎这次啊
She is the concubine who is escorting the emperor's grandson
是要护送皇孙的小妾
Going to Wangzhou
去望州呢
I'm just talking about the emperor's grandson
我就说那个皇孙
Not a thing
不是个东西
The enemy is now
大敌当前
He still thinks about women
他还想着女人
after i got hurt
我受伤后
The imperial court originally said
朝廷本来说
Give me twenty acres of farmland
要给我二十亩屯田
I total it up
我一合计
Growing food at home is also a way to survive.
回家种粮也是一条生路
But I didn't expect
但是没想到
The imperial court actually tricked people
朝廷竟然诓人
They took the fields
他们把田
Gave it to the emperor's son as an imperial palace
给了皇帝的儿子做皇庄
my old mother
我老母亲
This is how he was starved to death
就是这样被活活饿死的
I'm so angry
我一气之下
So he defected to Mingdai Village
就投奔了明岱寨
There is such a thing
竟然还有这种事
After Sun Jing's rebellion
孙靖造反后
Many villages were trampled by the army
很多村庄都被大军践踏
I don’t even know now
现如今都不知道
our village
我们村
Is there anyone alive?
还有没有活着的人
Seventeen Lang, you don’t know
十七郎 你不知道
I originally
我原先
I am a fortune teller in the village.
我是乡里头算命的呀
I can do it
我算是可以
You have to support your family, right?
养家糊口了吧
This court
这朝廷
It was forced to do corvée work several times
它数次征徭役
Several corvee expeditions
数次征徭役
I really can't live anymore
我实在是活不下去了
I
我
I just fell into the trap of others.
我这才落草为寇的呀
Our brothers here
咱们这儿的兄弟
Everyone has a bitter taste
个个都有一腔苦水
No matter who is surnamed Li, he will dominate the world
无论是姓李的坐天下
Still the old thief named Sun
还是姓孙的那个老贼
They don't even give us a way to survive.
都不给俺们活路
We
俺们
I had no choice but to go up the mountain and become a robber.
没办法才上山当强盗
Jushichiro
十七郎
Since you are here, you are here
既然你来都来了
Why don't you just be the big brother?
不如就当大哥
Take us
带着咱们
Let's go to Zhenxi Army together
一起去投奔镇西军
OK
好不好
Right, brother?
对不对 大哥
right
对
We regard you as our big brother
俺们奉你为大哥
Big brother big brother big brother
大哥 大哥 大哥
no no no
不不不
No need to be humble
不用谦让
Today is a good day
今儿就是良辰吉日
We just happened to burn incense and become sworn brothers
咱们正好烧香结义
OK OK
好 好 好
Just kill this girl and sacrifice her to heaven.
就把这女娘杀了祭天
Can't kill, can't kill
不能杀 不能杀
Can't kill
不能杀
Brother, why is this?
大哥 这是为何
who knows
谁知道
do you know
你们知道吗
I don’t know, I don’t know, I don’t know
不知道 不知道 不知道
because
因为
Who knows?
这谁知道啊
That's right
就是啊
do you know
你们知道吗
because she is
因为她是
The concubine of the emperor's grandson
皇孙的侍妾
but
但
She is my sweetheart
她是我的心上人
We are both in love
我们俩两情相悦
It's my sister-in-law
是阿嫂啊
It took a lot of effort to find the opportunity
好不容易才找到机会
Make an appointment to elope
相约私奔而去
Brother, why didn't you tell me earlier?
大哥 你为何不早说
This sister-in-law is still tied up.
这阿嫂还被绑着呢
How cold it is on the ground
地上多凉啊
Sister-in-law, Sister-in-law, Sister-in-law
阿嫂 阿嫂 阿嫂
Sister-in-law, let me untie you
阿嫂 我替你松绑
Aren't I embarrassed?
我这不是不好意思吗
I'm so sorry
真是抱歉抱歉
Sister-in-law is so offended
阿嫂 多有得罪
Laolan River Eighteen Bays
牢兰河水十八湾
The first bay is Silver Pine Beach
第一湾就是那银松滩
Fish fat in Yinsongtan
银松滩里的鱼儿肥
What's this
这是什么
Big brother
大哥
We are humble in the mountains
俺们山中简陋
I can't do it for you and my sister-in-law
不能为你和阿嫂
Get married
拜堂成亲
But this bridal chamber
不过这个洞房
But it’s indispensable
可是不能少的
Entering the bridal chamber
对 洞房 入洞房
Brother, don't be embarrassed
大哥 你不要不好意思
Come, come, come
来来来
Come in quickly. Come in quickly.
快进去 快进去
Come on, sister-in-law
快走吧 阿嫂
Come and go, come and go
来 去吧去吧
Let's go, let's go
走吧走吧走吧
go ahead
去吧
Brother, hurry up
大哥 抓紧
Brothers, good times are short
兄弟 良辰苦短
Let's go first
我们先走啦
Go, go, go
走走走
gone
走了
General Pei of the Zhenxi Army
镇西军的小裴将军
The concubine of the emperor's grandson Li Ni
皇孙李嶷的爱妾
Jushichiro Jushichiro
十七郎 十七郎
Jushichiro
十七郎
The brothers found it with great difficulty
兄弟们好不容易找到的
Flowers and candles in your bridal chamber
你洞房花烛
How could we not have this?
怎么能没有这个呢
hold
拿着
Don't keep my sister-in-law waiting.
别让阿嫂等急了
Thank you very much
好 谢谢啊
I'm leaving soon
快 我走了
This town is in the Western Army
这镇西军中
The famous Seventeenth Lang
赫赫有名的十七郎
That’s the emperor’s grandson Li Yi
就是皇孙李嶷
These bandits don't know
这帮山匪不知道
But do I know
但我可知道
Strange
奇怪了
That Zhao Youde
那个赵有德
I was also in Zhenxi Army before
之前也在镇西军
why doesn't he know
为什么他不知道
It turns out that some people
原来某些人
I was in the military before
之前一直在军中
incognito
隐姓埋名
But later the military merits accumulated to
但是后来军功累积到
When you want to be sealed for three generations
要荫封三代的时候
I can no longer hide it
就再也无法隐瞒下去了
But at that time
但是那个时候
Zhao Youde
赵有德
Already left the Zhenxi Army
已经离开镇西军了
Am I right?
我说得没错吧
so what
那又怎么样
You didn't expose me just now
你刚才没有拆穿我
how
怎么
Do you want to expose me now?
难道现在想拆穿我
I didn’t expect you would actually use it as a pretense
没想到你居然会假借
General Pei's name
小裴将军的名字
Even I was almost deceived by you
连我都差点被你骗了
If not so
若非如此
How can I hear it with my own ears?
怎么能亲耳听到
some people say
某些人说
She is the concubine of the emperor's grandson Li Ni
她是皇孙李嶷的爱妾呢
villain
小人
stand up
起来
I sleep on the bed and you sleep on the floor
我睡床上你睡地上
I've been struggling all day
我折腾了一天了
I need to take a good rest
我得好好歇息一下
I can handle it
我才能应付
You're so scheming
你这个诡计多端
A little liar who tells lies
满口谎言的小骗子
hurry up
快点
you are a gentleman
你是君子
You sleep on the floor
你睡地上吧
what you do
你做什么
What to do
什么做什么
Since you are my concubine
既然你都是我的爱妾了
Then we
那我们
sleeping on a bed
躺在一张床上睡觉
That's okay
也可以吧
lecher
登徒子
You've already scolded me like this
你都这么骂我了
Then I definitely can't
那我肯定不能
This false name is in vain
枉担这个虚名
My own peach
自己人 桃子
school lieutenant
校尉
Lieutenant, are you okay?
校尉 你没事吧
fine
没事
This person is so rude
此人如此无礼
I'll shoot him to death with one arrow to vent your anger.
我一箭射死他给你出气
OK
好啊
Your captain
你们家校尉
I've wanted to do this for a long time
早就想这么做了
But until now she
不过她到现在
None of them succeeded
都没有得逞
Do you want to try it?
你要不要试一下呀
you
你
stop
住手
It's time for me to say this
这句话到我说了
own people
自己人
problem occurs
出事了
Someone's calling
有人打上来了
big brother big brother
大哥 大哥
Big brother
大哥
What's wrong
怎么了
There is a brother outside bringing a message in
外边有兄弟传信儿进来
Said there was a large team of people
说有大队人马
Come to the mountain immediately to fight
马上杀上山来
What do you call yourself?
还自称是什么
To rebel against the governor's banner
讨逆大都督旗下
The army led by General Guo Zhi
郭直将军率领的大军
Said he wanted to take away our cottage
说要夺我们的山寨
kill us all
杀我们全部人
Are we going to be sacrificed to heaven?
拿我们祭天呢
listen to them fart
听他们放屁
It's okay, brother
没事 大哥
Our cottage is condescending
我们山寨居高临下
Easy to defend but difficult to attack
易守难攻
Brothers rely on the terrain
兄弟们凭借地势
You can also kill them without leaving a single piece of armor behind.
也能杀他们个片甲不留
Yeah
对 对 对
Leave no trace behind
片甲不留
Kill kill kill
杀 杀 杀
Don't lie
莫说大话
Second child
老二
Second brother
二哥
The one named Guo
那个姓郭的
He's an old acquaintance of ours.
是咱们的老熟人了
Just before
就是之前
General Guo, who has been stationed in Wangzhou
一直驻守望州的郭将军
It turned out to be him
原来是他
did not expect
没想到
He actually took refuge in Sun Jing
他竟然投靠了孙靖
That's really hard to do
那还真有点难办
The one named Guo
那个姓郭的
Birthplace: Inishi
出身硕西
But when it comes to the world’s military
但是论天下府兵
Let’s hold down the Western Army
咱们镇西军
Why are you afraid of other provinces?
何尝怕过其他诸府
Yes, yes
对呀 是 是
This is from my Zhenxi Army
这是我镇西军的
scout brothers
斥候兄弟
He followed Guo Zhi all the way tonight
他今夜一路跟着郭直
He also came to report to me
他也来向我报讯
There are still many people in Guo Zhi's remnant army
郭直残军还有不少人
And they are skilled with bows and arrows
且他们弓箭娴熟
head-on
硬碰硬
We will definitely suffer
我们肯定会吃亏
That Seventeenth Lang
那十七郎
Take this lady with you quickly
你赶快带着这位娘子
Let's go together
一起走吧
school lieutenant
校尉
You go back to the camp first
你先回营地
The young master is waiting for you in Bingzhou
公子在并州等你
To Shichiro, you should leave first.
对 十七郎 你先走吧
I'm here
这里有我
Too
也是
My brother who is a scout
我这个斥候出身的兄弟
He is best at fighting in dense forests
他最擅长在密林里作战
He will win
他必能战胜
Those remnant soldiers of Guo Zhi
郭直那些残兵
I'll stay and help too
我也留下来帮忙
This female envoy of mine is very good at war.
我这位女使极善兵法
keep her
把她留下来
I will definitely be able to help everyone
必能助大家一臂之力
Great. Thank you. Thank you.
太好了 谢谢 谢谢
yes
是啊
thank you
多谢
thank you all
多谢诸位
thank you thank you
多谢 多谢
thank you
多谢
I really can't walk anymore
我实在走不动了
You'd better hurry up
你还是赶紧
Go back to your Wangzhou City
回你的望州城去吧
Leave me alone
不用管我了
How can that be done?
那怎么行
You are my concubine
你身为我爱妾
How could I leave you alone?
我怎么能丢下你不管呢
If you continue to be so arrogant
你要是再如此口齿轻薄
Be careful I'll kill you
小心我杀了你
look
你看
You have the strength to kill people
你杀人的力气都有
But I don’t have the strength to walk.
却没力气走路啊
no
不行
I really can't walk anymore
实在走不动了
Think of something
你想法子吧
I won't leave
我不走了
I really have a way
我还真有个法子
But
不过呢
You have to cooperate with me
你得配合我
Let's go and change clothes.
走 换衣服吧
No one in the house
屋里没人
Are you okay?
好了没呀
immediately
马上
Why don't you just change your clothes?
你不就换个衣服吗
Why are you so lazy?
怎么这么磨蹭啊
I changed it
我换好了
alright
好了
Walk
走
Let's go
走吧
alright
好了
you
你
So white and clean
这么白白净净的
no
不行
come over
过来
What for?
干吗
Don't move
别动啊
What are you doing?
这干什么
Are you going to pretend to be a village woman?
你是要扮村妇
Do you look like a village woman?
你看着像村妇吗
What is this doing?
这又是做什么
You'll know later
等会儿你就知道了
tie into clothes
系到衣服里
Why
为什么
Of course I want you to pretend to be a pregnant woman
当然是让你扮孕妇啊
You have a big belly
你挺着个大肚子
So I can borrow a car
我才好去借车嘛
Don’t you want to leave?
你不是不想走吗
That's the husband
那为夫
I'll take you into the city by car
便带你坐车进城
pregnant woman
孕妇
hurry up
快点
How can I stop this?
这我怎么塞啊
can you hurry up
你能不能快点
It would be nice to have a car to sit in
有车坐就不错了
Too slow
还嫌慢
No hurries
急什么
Afraid that people don’t know
怕人家不知道
There is straw in your belly
你肚子里面是稻草啊
A gentleman talks but does not use his hands
君子动口不动手啊
I'm not a gentleman
我又不是君子
I'm a lady
我是淑女
you lady
你淑女
Look at you like this
你看你这模样
Which one of the virtuous and virtuous ones is related?
贤良淑德哪一个沾边
I let you say
我让你说
I'm warning you not to fight
我警告你别打了
I fought back
我还手了
Old lady, stop crying
老婆子 别哭了
The mountain goods are gone, we can fight again
山货没了咱们可以再打
Get angry with those people
跟那些人置气
not worth it
不值得
old man
老丈
Excuse me
请问
How far is it from Bingzhou?
这里离并州还有多远
Still far away
还远着呢
There's still more than a hundred miles to go
还有一百多里路呢
This injury on your face
您脸上这伤
What happened?
是怎么了吗
Forget it
别提了
Hurry up
快快快
Recently
这几天
Don't know what's going on
也不知道怎么回事
Officers and soldiers came from the mountain
山里面来了官兵
Still on the official road ahead
还在前面的官道上
Suddenly a checkpoint was set up
突然就设立了关卡
My wife and I
我跟老婆子
I was originally going to the market
本来是去赶集的
What to take
拿什么呀
Who knows that group of people
谁知道那群人
Worse than bandits
比土匪还凶
Eat roast rabbit tonight
今天晚上吃烤兔肉
bring here
拿过来
This is what we got at the market
这是我们拿到集市上
for salt
换盐的
hold
拿着
we all day long
我们成日里
Follow Governor Sun
跟着孙大都督
General Guo Zhi
旗下的郭直将军
crusade against rebellion
讨逆伐乱
What's wrong with eating some of your rabbits?
吃你几只兔子怎么了
roll
滚
Xiaolangjun
小郎君
Never take the official route
千万不要走官道
Those people are so bad
那群人坏得很啊
Big girl and little daughter-in-law
大姑娘 小媳妇
They won't let it go
他们是更不放过
Your wife is young
你家娘子年纪轻轻的
Say it again
再说
Scared the baby in her belly
吓到她肚子里的娃娃
That would be even more serious
那 那就更不得了了
In addition to officialdom
那除了官道
What other paths are there?
还有哪些小路
Can it be bypassed?
可以绕开吗
Go up the mountain from here
从这里上山
There is a path going west
往西面走有一条小路
But that's a long way around
但那就绕得远了
And the roads are all difficult to walk on.
而且都是山路 不好走
Wait until it gets dark
等天一落黑
It would be even worse to leave
就更不好走了
Thank you, husband
谢谢老丈
Remember not to take the official route
记住 别走官道
Don't take the official route
别走官道
It’s been a long time since I’ve eaten your steamed melon cheese.
很久没吃你蒸的蜜瓜酪了
I'll try it
我来尝尝
Not bad
不错 不错
What do you think of that Shi7ro?
你怎么看那个十七郎
Li Yi
李嶷啊
This person
这个人啊
He is in the royal family
他在皇家宗室里
Not obvious
委实不显
I heard
我听闻
He was very naughty at first
他当初非常的顽劣
Make the late emperor furious
让先帝大发雷霆
Demoted him to the army
将他贬到了军中去了
I asked someone to check the Ministry of War files.
我叫人查过兵部档案了
When he was demoted to suppress the Western Army,
他被贬去镇西军的同时
Pei Xian gave his youngest son
裴献将自己的小儿子
Pei Yuan
裴源
Conglong Wuwei
从龙武卫
Also transferred to the Zhenxi Army
也调到了镇西军中
thereafter
此后
Pei Yuan has always been with Li Yi
裴源一直和李嶷
inseparable
形影不离
Always on the same team
总在一队
Pei Xian, the old fox
裴献这个老狐狸
eyes higher than head
眼高于顶
He let his son
他让自己的儿子
follower
追随的人
It must not be underestimated
必然不可小视
But I heard
可是我听说
Pei Xian had ten sons in total
裴献共有十个儿子
Some are in the military
有的在军中
Some gave up martial arts and followed literature
有的弃武从文
Some became Taoist priests
有的却做了道士
As well-planned as the Grand Governor
像大都督这般筹谋周密
How could Pei Xian know?
裴献又怎知
Will the Grand Governor raise the flag of justice?
大都督会举起义旗呢
Since I don't know
既然不知道
How could he make plans so early?
他又怎会早早布局
to pay attention to one
去重视一个
Demoted to the army
被贬到军中
And what about the emperor’s grandson who has fallen out of favor?
而失宠的皇孙呢
What's wrong
怎么了
Why are my hands so hot?
手怎么这么烫
It's okay, let's go
没事 快走吧
Come and show me
来 给我看看
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
你怎么不早说
this is nothing
这没什么
gone
走了
How do you go like this?
你这样怎么走啊
Get up and carry you
起来 背你
Come up
上来
woke up
醒了
Do you want some water?
要不要喝点水
where is this
这是哪儿
What about a place like this?
这种地方呢
Usually when hunters go up to the mountains to hunt,
一般是猎户上山打猎时
For resting feet
歇脚用的
It was getting late just now
刚才天色已晚
I only found one herbal medicine
我就只找到了一种草药
I put it on you
给你敷上了
I don't know if it will work or not.
不知道管不管用
I'm not that squeamish
我没那么娇气
old woman
老婆子
do not Cry
别哭了
The mountain goods are gone, we can fight again
山货没了咱们可以再打
Get angry with those people
跟那些人置气
not worth it
不值得
Just don't think about it
你就别想了
What should I do if I get sick from this anger?
这气出病来怎么办
The trip is coming soon
行 马上到了
Old lady, please slow down a little bit.
老婆子 你慢一点
knew
知道了
old man
老丈
who
谁
Why is it you?
怎么是你们呢
Why are you here?
你们怎么会在这里啊
who is it
是谁啊
The young couple we met today
咱们今天碰到的小夫妻
You said it was a coincidence or not?
你说巧不巧
Yeah
是吗
It really is
还真是
Sit down, sit down
快坐 快坐
A little more generous
多盛一点
Multi-point meat
多加点肉
Taste the real pheasant
尝尝真正的山鸡的味道
Thank you, mother-in-law
谢谢婆婆
Drink more to warm yourself up
多喝点啊 暖暖身子
have a taste
尝尝
This pheasant
这山鸡啊
My old man just hit me
是我老头子刚打的
The soup is delicious
煮汤可好喝了
Serve more meat Serve some more meat
多盛点肉 盛点肉
Thank you, mother-in-law
谢谢婆婆
Eat more, eat more
多吃一点 多吃一点
My old man
我老头子呀
I also like to drink the soup I cook.
也爱喝我煮的汤
But it's a pity for me
不过可惜我呀
Couldn't give it to him
没能给他
Give birth to a son and a half daughter
生个一儿半女的
If only I had a daughter like you
要是有你这样一个闺女
How nice
多好啊
Come on old man
来 老头子
You have worked hard
你辛苦了
How about it
怎么样
Delicious to drink
好喝 好喝
You young people
你们少年人哪
Eat more meat
多吃点肉
I have to rush tomorrow
明天还要赶
long mountain road
很长时间的山路
Only when you are full can you have strength
吃饱了才有力气
By the way, husband
对了 老丈
It's so late
这都这么晚了
Why did you suddenly come back?
你们怎么突然又回来了
Forget it
别提了
My wife and I
我跟老婆子
I was originally going to the market
本来是去赶集的
The results of it
结果呢
The salt was not replaced
盐没换成
thing
东西
They were also snatched away by those officers and soldiers.
也被那些官兵给抢走了
The old lady thinks about things and is unwilling to give in.
老婆子左想右想不甘心
Don't force me
非逼着我
Go back to the mountains and wander around again
回山里再转转
Let's see if we can hunt a few more mountain tigers.
看能不能再打几只山货
The results of it
结果呢
I only caught this pheasant
只打到了这只山鸡
It's getting dark soon
眼看着天就要黑了
I know
我知道
There's a place to stay here
这里有个落脚的地方
did not expect
没想到
I also met you
还碰到了你们
Do you think this is fate?
你说 这是不是缘分呢
Yeah yeah
是啊 是啊
yes
是啊
Just heard the noise
刚听到动静
I thought he was a bad guy
还以为是歹人呢
And you
你呢
Lead your wife on the way
领着你家娘子赶路
It is necessary to have multiple eyes
多个心眼是应该的
This world
这世道
Very messy
乱得很
yes
是呀
drink soup drink soup
喝汤 喝汤
eat more
多吃一点
Come
来
old woman
老婆子
You eat too
你也吃
You eat, you eat
你吃 你吃
You eat some
你吃点
Come again, come again
再来 再来
Someone is coming
有人要来了
There are people riding horses
还有人骑着马
Eighty percent of achievements are official.
八成就是官道上的
That group of officers and soldiers
那群官兵
old woman
老婆子
Get up, get up
快起来 快起来
What's wrong
怎么了
Those two people might be hiding in front
那两个人或许就藏在前面
Surrounded by heavy arrows and crossbows
命重箭弓弩围起来
yes
是
This is what I was fine with in the past few years
这是我前几年待着没事
Dig your own cellar
自己挖的地窖
It was originally used to store mountain goods.
原本是存山货的
size
大小
Just enough to hide two people
正好能够藏下两个人
you
你
Take your wife with you immediately
马上领着你家娘子
Hurry down and take shelter
赶紧下去躲一躲
right
对
no
不行
It’s you, my husband, who wants to hide.
要躲也是老丈您
Hide in with your mother-in-law
和婆婆躲进去
That group of people all know us.
那群人都认识我们
He won't do anything to us
不会拿我们怎么样的
But you two are strangers
可你们两个是生人
If discovered by officers and soldiers
如果被官兵发现
On the contrary, it is more dangerous
反倒更危险
My wife and I can't escape either.
我和老婆子也脱不了身
Yeah
对对对
Get down quickly
赶紧下去
Come on, come on, good boy
快 快快 好孩子
Quick, quick, quick
快快快 快点
My daughter is not afraid
闺女 不怕
hurry up
快点 快点
Search if there is a stranger
搜 若有生人
Kill immediately without mercy
立刻格杀勿论
Come
来
Shop here
铺这儿
quick
快
Junye
军爷
We are hunters in the mountains
我们是山里的猎户
Have you seen a young man?
有没有看到个少年郎
Look fair and clean
长得白白净净
like a scholar
像一个读书人
Junye
军爷
Our ten miles and eight villages
咱们这十里八乡
Where are the scholars?
哪有什么读书人呢
Mention reading
提起读书
Just Mr. Shan in town
还就镇上的单先生
What are you talking about?
啰唆什么
Say or not
说不说
Master, please spare your life, Master.
军爷 饶命啊 军爷
We really don’t know anything
我们真的什么都不知道啊
take them out
把他们带出去
Take a walk
走 走
Walk
走
Junye Junye
军爷 军爷
Spare your life, Master
饶命啊 军爷
we don't know anything
我们什么都不知道
do not know anything
什么都不知道
Are you really
你们真的
Don’t know anything?
什么都不知道吗
Really don't know anything
真的什么都不知道
good
好
Since you don't know anything
既然你们什么都不知道
Then let you go back
那就放你们回去吧
loosen them
松开他们
Let's go
走吧
Thank you, Junye
谢谢军爷
Walk
走
Where are they?
他们人呢
died
死了
What
什么
I just went out to see
我刚才出去看
Both men are dead
两个人都死了
Are you crazy
你是不是疯了
Why did you sting me with a needle?
为什么拿针刺晕我
If you hadn't stung me with a needle and knocked me out
如果不是你拿针刺晕我
they won't die
他们就不会死
you know outside
你知道外面
How many archers are there?
有多少弓箭手吗
Found out they were harboring us
发现他们窝藏我们
if we go out recklessly
如果我们鲁莽出去
It's simply too late
根本就来不及
On the contrary, they will be killed immediately
反倒会让他们立刻毙命
what about now
那现在呢
If I had come out to save him at that time
如果当时出来救
There's still a chance
就还有一丝机会
But you don't want to give it a try
你却不愿一试
you
你
He's just a rat who is greedy for life and afraid of death.
就是个贪生怕死的鼠辈
people like you
你这样的人
Still have the nerve to drink soup
还有脸喝汤
ungrateful villain
忘恩负义的小人
I am
我就是
just kill me
你杀了我吧
benefactor
恩人
I was wrong today
今日是我错了
someday
他日
I will definitely avenge you
我定会为你们报仇